YINGXIN ZHOU

Room 738, 7/F, Cheng Yu Tung Building 12 Chak Cheung Street, Shatin, N. T., Hong Kong S.A.R. ◆ +852 9497 5200 ◆ yingxinzhou@link.cuhk.edu.hk

- Professional Summary -----

A highly-motivated research assistant specializing in Information Systems at the Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), with 17 months of work experience in empirical research. Conducting astute data analysis with machine learning techniques and Python. Clearly communicating findings from assessment, evaluation, and data processing to support research projects. Having a strong academic background in e-business and business analytics and awarded multiple scholarships. Having a working paper in preparation for submission.

EDUCATION -

Master of Science: Business Analytics, 08/2018 - 07/2019

The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) - Hong Kong S.A.R.

- GPA: 3.66/4.00, Admission Scholarships (Top 5 out of 120), Dean's List (Top 20%)
- Selected coursework: Business Intelligence Techniques and Applications (Grade A), Data Mining for Managers (Grade A)

Bachelor of Management: Electronic Business, 08/2014 - 06/2018

Sun Yat-sen University (SYSU) - Guangzhou, China

- GPA 3.8/4.0, The Hes Scholarships (Top 5%), three Third Prize Scholarships (Top 20%)
- Selected coursework: Computer Algorithmic Language Experiment (98/100), Experimenting Research (95/100), Data Mining and Business Intelligence (89/100), Information Economics (89/100)

PUBLICATION

Zhou, Yingxin and Keongtae Kim, "To Move or Not to Move: Geography of Initial Coin Offerings," In preparation for submission at *Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice*

RESEARCH AND WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant (Full-time), 09/2019 – Current

The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Supervisor: Prof. KIM Keongtae – Hong Kong S.A.R.

- Analyzed data with machine learning techniques like topic modeling and sentimental analysis with Python
- Collected quantitative data from multiple online platforms like LinkedIn and Kickstarter through web scraping in R language
- Conducted preliminary data analysis, wrote initial drafts and literature reviews

Research Assistant (Part-time), 12/2016 – 12/2016

Sun Yat-sen University, Supervisor: Prof. LIN Bin – Guangzhou, China

- Collected basic data of 500 listed companies' newly issued shares through firms' reports
- Analyzed data about shares and target assets

AWARDS AND HONORS

- The Dean's List of CUHK (Top 20%), 11/2019
- The Admission Scholarships of CUHK (Top 5 out of 120), 08/2018
- The Hes Scholarships of SYSU (Top 5%), 08/2018
- The Third Prize Scholarship of SYSU (Top 20%), Yr 2015, 2016, 2017
- The Second Grade Prize in Youth Research Competition of SYSU (Top 5 out of 120), 05/2016
- The Excellent Volunteer in the SYSU Enrollment Promotion Activities, 04/2016
- The Second Grade Prize in the Global Management Challenge China Competition (Top 1%), 01/2016

OTHER INFORMATION AND SKILLS

Administration Experience

• Deputy Director at the Student Activity Centre of SYSU, 06/2016 - 06/2017

Volunteering Experience

- Team leader of the "Lighting Up Music Dreams" Public Welfare Crowdfunding Project, 09/2016 12/2016
- Volunteer of the Buddy Program for foreign students at SYSU, 05/2016 05/2017

Certifications

- Certification of Securities Professional, Securities Association of China
- Certificate of Accounting Profession, Bureau of Finance of Baiyun District, Guangzhou Municipality

Language Skills

- GMAT total score 740/800, 97% below
- IELTS overall band score 7.5/9.0
- Native speaker of Cantonese and Mandarin Chinese

Computer Skills

• Python, R, Stata, Weka, Gretl, MongoDB, SQL, SPSS, C++, Arena, Access, AutoCAD, and MS Office